Arrays, just like any other variable type,
数组就像其它类型的变量
can be passed in as arguments to functions.
能够作为参数输入到函数中
They can also be returned as return types.
也能作为返回类型被函数返回
Say for example, we want to create a function that calculates
比如 我们想创建一个函数
the average temperature from an array of temperatures.
计算一个温度数组的平均温度
Let's name our function, calculateAverage.
把函数命名为 calculateAverage
It will take in an input of an array of doubles and it would return a single double,
函数以一个双精度数组为参数并返回一个双精度数
which is the average value of all the doubles in the input array.
而该数即输入数组中所有双精度数的平均值
Our function definition would look something like this,
函数定义就像这样
public double calculateAverage, and
public double calculateAverage
a parameter of an array of doubles just called, temperatures.
然后是一个双精度数组参数 叫做 temperatures
The first thing we need to do is figure out
首先我们需要弄清楚
how many temperature values are stored inside this array.
这个数组里有多少个温度值
Because there are parsed in as a parameter,
因为这些值被当作参数输入进来了
we don't really know how many elements are stored in it.
所以我们不知道数组里存放了多少元素
To figure that out,
为了明确这一点
we could type in the array name followed by the key word length.
我们可以输入数组名 后面写上关键字 length
This basically counts the number of items inside
这会计算数组里有多少项
that array and stores it into our variable, size.
并将项数存放到变量 size 里
Next, to calculate the average,
接下来要计算平均值
we need to add up all the items inside the array first.
我们要先把数组里的所有项加起来
We can do that by declaring this total variable of type,
为此 我们可以声明这个变量 total
double, and initialize it to zero,
它是双精度型的 然后将变量初始化为 0
and then we follow that with a loop.
接着创建一个循环
Our loop counter, i, starts from zero and keeps going as long as i is less than size,
循环计数器为 i 从 0 开始计数 直到 i 不再小于 size 为止
which we have calculated earlier.
而 size 我们已经算好了
Now, inside that loop,
在循环里
we could continue to add to our total variable the temperatures of i.
我们可以将 temperatures [i] 的值不断与变量 total 相加
Notice how I have used the loop counter as our index in our array here.
注意这里我是怎么用循环计数器当数组索引的
This is basically because our loop counter starts from
这是因为循环计数器从 0 开始
zero and keeps incrementing by one every time,
每次都会加 1
which means using this inside the loop,
这就意味着在循环里用这个
we're accessing every single item in the temperatures array.
我们就可以访问温度数组里的每一项
And because we're adding it to our total variable,
由于我们把它加到了变量 total 里
by the end of this loop,
所以等循环结束
total would have the total sum of the values inside this temperatures array.
total 会等于这个温度数组里所有值的总和
To calculate the average then,
接下来计算平均值
we just need to divide that by our size,
我们只需让 total 除以 size
which is the number of elements inside the array.
即除以数组元素的数量
Then we could safely return our average calculation as
就可以安全地返回出平均值的计算结果
a result of our function. That looks great.
来作为函数的结果 看起来不错
Let's trace it with an example array of doubles to see if it actually works.
我们来跟踪一个双精度数组 以此为例 看看代码能否奏效
If temperatures was equal to this array here with those four different temperatures,
如果 temperatures 等于这个包含着四个不同温度的数组
then once we start calculating the length,
那么等我们开始计算长度
it would set our size to four because we have four different values there.
它就会将 size 设为 4 因为这里有四个不同的值
The next step is to initialize total to zero and then we step into the loop.
下一步是将 total 初始化为 0 然后进入循环
Let's draw this table here and keep track of our loop counter,
画出这个表格 以便跟踪循环计数器、
what's it's accessing inside the array,
数组里被访问的对象
and the updated total value every step.
以及每一步更新出来的 total 值
The first thing that happens is initializing i to zero,
首先是把 i 初始化为 0
so i becomes zero.
于是 i 变为 0
And because i is less than size,
由于 i 小于 size
which is four in this case,
也就是小于 4
we step inside the loop and run this statement here.
所以进入循环 执行这个语句
What happens inside the loop,
在循环里
is we're trying to access temperatures of i.
我们会试着访问 temperatures [i]
i is zero at this case so we're trying to access temperatures of zero,
由于 i 为 0 所以我们要访问的是 temperatures [0]
which is the first item in the array which is equal to 75.
也就是数组里的第一项 该项为 75
Once we get that value,
一旦获取了这个值
we add that to total because we're using the plus equal sign here.
我们就把它和 total 相加 因为我们这里用的是加号等号
And total was initialized to zero so once we add 75 to zero, total becomes 75.
而 total 初始值为 0 所以我们给 0 加 75 后 total 就变为 75
And then we reach this closing brackets of our loop so we go back up and increment i.
然后就到了循环的右括号 于是回到这上面来 给 i 增量
Once we run the increment i instruction,
等我们执行完 i 增量指令
i increases by 1 from 0 to 1.
i 就会加 1 从 0 变为 1
The next thing that happens, is we check if i is less than the size.
接下来就是判断 i 是否小于 size
i is one and size is four so that means we're allowed to step inside the loop.
i 为 1 而 size 为 4 所以我们能够进入循环
Inside our loop, we're accessing temperatures of i,
在循环里 访问 temperatures [i]
which is now 1,
现在 i 为 1
and temperatures of 1 is equal to 73.
所以 temperatures [i] 等于 73
At that case, we're accessing 73 and then we're adding
也就是我们访问了 73
this temperatures of i to total using this plus equal sign.
然后用加号等号把这个  temperatures [i] 和 total 相加
So we're basically adding 73 to 75 and total gets updated to 148.
也就是 73 加 75 total 更新为 148
Again, we reach this closing brackets, so we go back up,
于是我们又一次到了右括号 再回来
increment i by one making it from 1 to 2,
给 i 加 1 使其从 1 变为 2
and then we go back and check if i is less than size.
然后再次判断 i 是否小于 size
Size is four so that's still true so we step inside the loop again.
size 为 4 所以条件仍为真 所以我们再进入循环
Temperatures of i at that point is temperatures of 2,
temperatures [i] 这个时候变成  temperatures [2]
so that's the item of index two here which is 72,
而这里索引 2 关联的项为 72
and then we're adding that to our total.
将其与 total 相加
We have updated total from 148 to 220.
将 total 值从 148 更新为 220
We reach the closing bracket, go back up,
到达右括号 再回来
increment i from 2 to 3 and then we're comparing it with
将 i 从 2 增加为 3 并与 size 进行比较
the size and 3 is still less than 4 so we step inside our loop,
3 仍小于 4 所以进入循环
access our temperatures of 3,
访问 temperatures [3]
which is 80 at that point,
也就是 80
and add that to total making it from 220 to 300.
将其与 total 相加 使 total 从 220 变为 300
Then at the last iteration,
然后是最后一次迭代
once we get this closing bracket,
到了右括号
we go back up, increment i,
回来 给 i 增量
which makes it four.
使其变为 4
But now, four is no longer less than size so we do not step into
现在 4 不再小于 size 所以我们不进入循环
that loop and we basically just jump all the way down to the closing bracket down here.
直接跳到这下面的右括号
Now that we're done with the loop,
现在我们不再进行循环了
we calculate the average by dividing total with size.
那就来计算平均值 让 total 除以 size
Total ended up being 300 and size started as four so 300 divided by four becomes 75,
total 最后是 300 而 size一直都为 4 所以 300 除以 4 等于 75
and that's the value that gets stored into
而这个值会被赋给变量 average
the variable average so we can safely return that as the result of the function.
由此我们可以安全地返回该值 作为函数的结果
Knowing the size of the array is very handy in many occasions.
知道数组的大小在很多时候都很方便
We've seen how to use it as the upper limit in a loop but there's
我们已经知道怎么拿它当循环上限用
a more serious problem that could happen if you just ignore the size of your array.
但如果你忽略了数组的大小 可能会出现更严重的问题
Imagine we're accessing different numbers in this array here.
假设我们要访问这个数组里的值
We know that it has four numbers in it,
我们知道这个数组有 4 个值
which means the indices start from 0 all the way with 3.
也就是说 索引从 0 开始一直增加到 3
And we've already seen how we can detect
我们已经知道要怎么用关键字 length
the number of items in an array using the length keyword.
来检测数组项数了
If we run this statement here on this array,
如果执行这个语句 对该数组进行操作
then length would actually calculate there are to be four items and size becomes four.
length 就会计算出这里有四项 于是 size 变为 4
But say we ignore this size variable and try to access the item with index 10,
但假设我们忽略了这个变量 size  试图用索引 10 来访问数组项
which obviously doesn't exist in the array.
而显然 数组里并没有这一项
Once you try to run this program,
一旦你运行这个程序
Java would give an error saying that this index is beyond the bounds of the array.
Java 就会提示出错 指出该索引不在数组范围内
But since we have this variable size now,
不过我们现在有了变量 size
we know how many items exist in the array and adding
我们就知道了数组里有多少项
something as simple as this if condition around this print line statement,
加一个像这样简单的 if 条件给这个 println 语句
we can check if the number of index that we're trying to
我们就可以判断要访问的索引
access is indeed smaller than our size.
是否小于数组大小
In a case where the array looks something like this,
如果是像这样的数组
this if condition would evaluate to false and it would not run the statement at all.
这个 if 条件就会判为假 因此不会执行语句
However, if another array had more than ten items,
然而 如果有一个超过十项的数组
then this if condition would actually evaluate to
那么这个 if 条件就会判为真
true and the statement would print the tenth item normally.
语句会如常输出第十项
Always be aware of your array bounds.
所以要时刻注意数组范围
The first thing you should do when dealing with arrays
处理数组 你要做的第一件事
is try to figure out how many items are in
就是弄清楚里面包含了多少项
there and always check before accessing
在访问任一项之前 要记得检查
any item if it's within the bounds of the array or not.
该项是否在数组范围内